SUNGHEE YUN

sunghee.yun@gmail.com

Profile

I am Co-founder & CTO of AI Technology and Product Strategy @ Erudio Bio, Inc. with expertise in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Product and Technology Strategy. I have led AI and optimization projects in the fields such as semiconductor design / manufacturing / testing, strategic marketing and sales, e-commerce, industrial AI, and AI-enhanced biotech based on my fundamental understanding of the inner workings of and insight into AI with knowledge on convex optimization underpinning all AI algorithms.

My strength lies in applying core AI technologies such as large language model (LLM) and generative AI (genAI) for development and productionization of a number of software and services to many customers for B2B and B2C business. I am also consulted for state and government policy-making with topics such as potential changes of labor market driven by of AI technology, ethical, social and political issues on AI, and supply chain and manufacturing of AI semiconductor chips including CPU, GPU, and AI accelerators.

Before joining Erudio Bio, Inc., I co-founded Gauss Labs Inc., an industrial AI start-up company, as CTO & Head of Global R&D. I led many high-profile AI projects at Amazon increasing revenue by 200 million USD via Amazon Mobile Shopping App. Prior to Amazon, I worked for Samsung Electronics leading AI and optimization projects for semiconductor design, manufacturing, and testing.

WORK AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & CTO - AI Technology & Product Strategy, Erudio Bio, Inc. Dec-2023 – Present

 AI Technology, and Product Strategy to develop and productionize AI-enhanced multiplomic multiplexing bio data platform

Adjunct Professor, Electronic Engineering Department, Sogang UniversityMar-2020 – PresentAdvisory Professor, Information and Communication Engineering, DGISTFeb-2020 – Present

• Consultation on academic direction, industry trend in Silicon Valley, social scientific / ethical / legal issues of AI & special lectures and seminars

Network Expert, Gerson Lehrman Gruop (GLG), New York City, U.S.A. Feb-2022 – Present

• Help clients solve their toughest business and technical challenges around manufacturing profit and sales improvement, e-commerce customer engagement level improvement, and AI technology in biotech industry

Co-founder & CTO - Senior Fellow, Gauss Labs Inc., Palo Alto, CA. U.S.A May-2000 - Nov-2023 VP - Fellow, SK hynix Sep-2020 - Jun-2021

• Business, Product & Tech Development / Operate US Headquarters

Senior Applied Scientist, Amazon.com, Inc., Vancouver, BC, Canada Nov-2018 – Aug-2020

- AI for Mobile Shopping App Main Menu Personalization system creating revenue by 200MM USD
- TestBot AI agents patching and updating software test scenarios

Principal Engineer, Software R&D Center, Samsung Electronics

Dec-2016 – Jun-2017

• Decentralized Federated AI for Internet of Things (IoT)

Principal Engineer, Strategic Sales & Marketing Team, Samsung Electronics Dec-2015 – Dec-2016

• AI for Sales Forecasting of world-wide NAND Flash and DRAM markets

Principal Engineer, Design Technology Team, Samsung Electronics Mar-2012 – Nov-2015

• AI for Optimal Scheduling System for Test & Package Factories in Suzhou, China,

• Generic AI & Optimization Platform for automatization of semiconductor design & manufacturing

Senior Engineer, CAE Team, Semiconductor R&D Center, Samsung Electronics Dec-2004 – Feb-2012

- NAND Flash Memory Core Operation Optimization achieving 10% accuracy improvement
- Generic Digital/Analog/Mixed-signal Circuit Optimization
- High density DRAM failure rate estimation achieving > 100X prediction time reduction

Research Assistant, EE Department, Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.

Mar-1999 - Nov-2004

• Multi-objective Logic Circuits Design using Convex Optimization

Development Engineer, Voyan Technology, Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

Sep-2000 - Aug-2001

• Digital Subscriber Line (DSL) Diagnosis & Length Adjustable Transmission Line Emulator

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Electrical Engineering - Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd	Sep-2001 - Nov-2004
Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.	
M.S., Electrical Engineering - Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd	Sep-1998 - Jun-2000
Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.	
B.S., Electrical Engineering - Magna Cum Laude	Mar-1994 - Feb-1998
Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea	
Honors and Awards	
• Best Invention Award at Amazon.com, Inc.	2019
• Best Paper Award at Samsung Semiconductor Technical Paper Award	2011
• Best Paper Award at Samsung Group Best Paper Award	2005
• Best Paper Award at International Symposium on Quality Electronic Design (ISQ	ED) 2005
• Full Scholarship from Samsung Electronics	2001 - 2004
• Samsung Frontier Membership	1999
• Ranked 2nd in the Ph.D. Qualifying Examination, Stanford University	1999
• Full Scholarship from Korean Foundation for Advanced Study (KFAS)	1998-2000
• Graduated with Honors - Magna Cum Laude, Seoul National University (SNU)	1998
• Full Scholarship from Seoul National University (SNU)	1994 – 1998
• Ranked 2nd in University Entrance Examination, Seoul National University (SNU	1994
• Graduated with Honors - Summa Cum Laude, Seoul Science High School	1993
• Bronze Medal at Asian Pacific Mathematical Olympiad (APMO)	1992
• Silver Medal at Korea Mathematical Olympiad (KMO)	1992

INVITED SEMINARS AND LECTURES

- "Applied Statistics Invited Seminar LLM & genAI Technology, Industry, and Market" invited by Yonsei University
 10-Jul-2024
- "Samsung Flash Design Team Invited Seminar Industrial AI & its applications in manufacturing" invited by Samsung Semiconductor 27-Jun-2024
- "SNU CSE Invited Seminar LLM & genAI Technology, Industry, and Some Important Questions" invited by Seoul National University (SNU) 25-Jun-2024
- "BK Intelligence System Semiconductor Invited Seminar LLM & genAI Technology, Industry, and Some Important Questions" invited by Sogang University
 24-Jun-2024

• "2024 LINC 3.0 + GSAI Joint Seminar - Industrial AI - Best Practices in Semiconductor Manuinvited by Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)	ufacturing" 9-Jun-2024
• "SAIT AIRC Seminar: LLM & getnAI - Technology, Business, and AI Markets" invited by Advanced Institute of Technology (SAIT)	Samsung 2024
• "DGIST Seminar: LLM & getnAI - Technology, Business, and AI Markets" invited by EE Dep Daegu Gyeongbuk Institute of Science and Technology (DGIST)	artment of 2024
• "Cryptography Seminar: Industrial AI Technology in Manufacturing" - SNU Math Department	
• "SNU Data Science (DS) Seminar: Industrial AI Technology" - SNU DS Graduate School	2023
• "EE/CS Seminar: Manufacturing AI Problems and Solutions" invited by SNU	2023
• "BK4 Seminar: Manufacturing AI Problems and Solutions" invited by Sogang University	2022
• "Time-series Machine Learning in Manufacturing" invited by Postech	2022
• "Time-series Learning and Software Platform for Manufacturing AI" invited by DGIST	2022
• "AI Frontier Summit: AI in Manufacturing and Industry Areas" invited by KICS	2021
• "Special Lecture: Electrical Engineer in the age of AI" invited by Sogang University	2021
• "Future Creation Seminar: The Future of AI" invited by Amore Pacific	2020
• "Reinforcement Learning and its Applications" invited by School of Business of UBC	2018
• "Convex Optimization for Machine Learning (ML)" invited by SNU	2018
• "Convex Optimization for Artificial Intelligence (AI)" invited by Amazon ML Meetings	2018
• "KCC Tutorial: Convex Optimization for Decentralized Machine Learning" invited by KCC 20	
• "Convex Optimization for Machine Learning" invited by Samsung DRAM Development Lab	2017
• "Introduction to Convex Optimization and its Applications" invited by Kyung Hee University	2013
• "Convex Optimization and its Applications" invited by SNU	2008
• "Circuit Design via Geometric Programming" invited by SNU	2005
• "Convex Optimization and its Application in Circuit Design" invited by Samsung Electronics	2002
Patents	
• Systems and Methods for Process Monitoring and Control	2023
\bullet Testbot AI agent: automatic software test scenario patch and modification system	2020
• Method of testing semiconductor memory device, test device, and computer readable recording	~
for recording test program for semiconductor memory device	2017
Method and system for designing 3D semiconductor package	2014
 Methodology for estimating statistical distribution characteristics of physical parameters of sem device 	iconductor 2009
$\bullet \ \ {\rm Methodology} \ \ {\rm for} \ \ {\rm estimating} \ \ {\rm statistical} \ \ {\rm distribution} \ \ {\rm characteristics} \ \ {\rm of} \ \ {\rm product} \ \ {\rm parameters}$	2007
\bullet Length adjustable transmission line emulators with simple RLC circuits	2001
Teaching Experience	
Amazon Lecturer Machine Learning University, Amazon	2018-2020
• AI Mathematical Fundamentals, AI Data Science, Advanced Machine Learning Courses	
Samsung Electronics Lecturer Samsung Electronics	2005-2017
• Convex Optimization for AI, Machine Learning & AI	
• Numerical Linear Algebra for ML, Advanced Statistics	
Teaching Assistant Stanford University	1999-2002
• Linear Dynamical Systems, Convex Optimization	